export const Teams = {
  Alpha: "A",
  Omega: "Î©",
};

const CategoryData = [
  {
    name: "Genesis",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "In the beginning god created the ____ and the earth.",
        answer: "heavens",
      },
      {
        question: "God called the light '___'",
        answer: "day",
      },
      {
        question: "The ____ was more cunning than any beast of the field.",
        answer: "serpent",
      },
      {
        question: "They sewed ____ leaves to cover themselves.",
        answer: "fig",
      },
      {
        question:
          "God removed Adam and Eve from the garden so they would not eat from the ____.",
        answer: "tree of life",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Who done it?",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who was sold into slavery by his brothers?",
        answer: "Joseph",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who brought down a Philistine temple, killing both himself and his captors?",
        answer: "Samson",
      },
      {
        question: "Who is known for striking a rock to bring forth water?",
        answer: "Moses",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who, as a prophet and judge of Israel, anointed both Saul and David as kings?",
        answer: "Samuel",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who is known for leading a small group of men with torches and trumpets to defeat the Midianites?",
        answer: "Gideon",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Miracles",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who walked on water alongside Jesus?",
        answer: "Peter",
      },
      {
        question: "Jesus's first miracle was turning?",
        answer: "water to wine",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In what city was a paralyzed man was lowered through a roof to be healed by Jesus?",
        answer: "Capernaum",
      },
      {
        question:
          "This prophet called upon God to send fire from heaven to consume a water-soaked sacrifice.",
        answer: "Elijah",
      },
      {
        question: "What prophet caused the Jordan River to stop flowing?",
        answer: "Elisha",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Gospel",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What was the last thing that Jesus uttered?",
        answer: "It is finished",
      },
      {
        question: "What was written on the sign placed on Jesus's cross?",
        answer: "Jesus of Nazareth  King of the Jews",
      },
      {
        question: "Who was the first to see Jesus after his resurrection?",
        answer: "Mary Magdalene",
      },
      {
        question:
          "On which hill was Jesus crucified, also known as the 'Place of the Skull'?",
        answer: "Golgotha",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who was the criminal released instead of Jesus by Pontius Pilate?",
        answer: "Barabbas",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Revelation",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "The number of the beast.",
        answer: "666",
      },
      {
        question: "How many seals are opened?",
        answer: "7",
      },
      {
        question: "Creatures with 'eyes all around, even under its wings.'",
        answer: "cherubim",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which color of the Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse is associated with famine?",
        answer: "black",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What entities are thrown into the lake of fire at the end of time?",
        answer: "death and hades",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Finish that verse!",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "I am the way, the truth, and the ____.",
        answer: "life",
      },
      {
        question: "The fear of the Lord is the beginning of ____.",
        answer: "wisdom",
      },
      {
        question: "I can do all this through him who gives me ____.",
        answer: "strength",
      },
      {
        question: "But seek first his kingdom and his ____.",
        answer: "righteousness",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness and ____.",
        answer: "self-control",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "How many?",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "How many commandments?",
        answer: "10",
      },
      {
        question: "How many days did God take to create the world?",
        answer: "6",
      },
      {
        question: "How many disciples did Jesus have?",
        answer: "12",
      },
      {
        question: "How many plagues were inflicted upon Egypt?",
        answer: "10",
      },
      {
        question: "Jesus used 5 loaves and _ fish to feed the multitude.",
        answer: "2",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Books",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "The last book in the bible.",
        answer: "Revelation",
      },
      {
        question: "The book after Psalm.",
        answer: "Proverbs",
      },
      {
        question: "The 3rd Gospel book.",
        answer: "Luke",
      },
      {
        question: "____ of the apostles.",
        answer: "Acts",
      },
      {
        question: "David kills Goliath in this book.",
        answer: "1 Samuel",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Where?",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "God took man and put him in the garden of _____.",
        answer: "Eden",
      },
      {
        question: "Our citizenship is in?",
        answer: "Heaven",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The people shouted, and the trumpets were blown, and the walls of this city fell down flat.",
        answer: "Jericho",
      },
      {
        question: "Jesus of?",
        answer: "Nazareth",
      },
      {
        question: "Where is he who has been born king of the Jews?",
        answer: "Bethlehem",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Bio",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Mother of Jesus, chosen by God for miraculous birth.",
        answer: "Mary",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Faithful builder of the Ark, saved family and animals from the great flood.",
        answer: "Noah",
      },
      {
        question: "Led Israelites from slavery, received Ten Commandments.",
        answer: "Moses",
      },
      {
        question: "Shepherd to king, wrote Psalms, defeated Goliath.",
        answer: "David",
      },
      {
        question:
          "This Jewish woman became Persia's queen and courageously unveiled her identity to prevent her people's annihilation.",
        answer: "Esther",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Who said it?",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Love your neighbor as yourself.",
        answer: "Jesus",
      },
      {
        question: "My God sent his angel, and he shut the mouths of the lions.",
        answer: "Daniel",
      },
      {
        question: "The Lord is my shepherd.",
        answer: "David",
      },
      {
        question:
          "I baptize you with water for repentance, but after me comes one who is more powerful than I, whose sandals I am not worthy to carry.",
        answer: "John the Baptist",
      },
      {
        question: "Wisdom is more precious than rubies.",
        answer: "Solomon",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Dream Big",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Who dreamed of a ladder reaching heaven with angels ascending and descending?",
        answer: "Jacob",
      },
      {
        question: "Who dreamed of sheaves of grain bowing to their sheaf?",
        answer: "Joseph",
      },
      {
        question: "Who asked God for wisdom in a dream?",
        answer: "Solomon",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who dreamed of his descendants being as numerous as the stars in the sky?",
        answer: "Abraham",
      },

      {
        question: "Who dreamed of a giant statue that troubled him?",
        answer: "King Nebuchadnezzar",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Just Do It",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Who immediately left his tax collection booth to follow Jesus?",
        answer: "Matthew",
      },
      {
        question: "Who showed great faith by offering his son as a sacrifice?",
        answer: "Abraham",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who experienced a radical transformation on the road to Damascus?",
        answer: "Saul",
      },
      {
        question: "Who boldly confronted the prophets of Baal on Mount Carmel?",
        answer: "Elijah",
      },
      {
        question: "Who fearlessly confronted King David about his sin?",
        answer: "Nathan",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Exodus",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What was the miraculous food provided to the Israelites in the wilderness?",
        answer: "Manna",
      },
      {
        question: "What body of water did the Israelites cross on dry land?",
        answer: "Red Sea",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the name of Moses' brother who served as his spokesperson?",
        answer: "Aaron",
      },
      {
        question: "What did Moses' staff turn into as a sign before Pharaoh?",
        answer: "Serpent",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What mountain did Moses ascend to receive the Ten Commandments?",
        answer: "Mount Sinai",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Parables",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "In the parable of the Good ____, who helps the wounded man?",
        answer: "Samaritan",
      },
      {
        question: "Parable of the ____ virgins.",
        answer: "10",
      },
      {
        question: "Parable of the Unforgiving ____.",
        answer: "servant",
      },
      {
        question: "In the parable of the sower, what do the birds represent?",
        answer: "satan",
      },
      {
        question:
          "'____ of Great Price' parable tells of a man who sold all he had to buy a valuable ____?",
        answer: "pearl",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Famous Duos",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Who were the brothers known for their rivalry, with one offering a better sacrifice to God?",
        answer: "Cain and Abel",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which two spies were sent by Moses to scout the land of Canaan?",
        answer: "Joshua and Caleb",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which two brothers were known for their wrestling and the story of the birthright?",
        answer: "Jacob and Esau",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who were the first apostles brothers called by Jesus while they were fishing?",
        answer: "Peter and Andrew",
      },
      {
        question: "Who were the two disciples known as the 'Sons of Thunder'?",
        answer: "James and John",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Symbols and Meanings",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Which symbol in the Bible represents the sacrifice of Jesus Christ?",
        answer: "Cross",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which symbol signifies the presence of the Holy Spirit and peace?",
        answer: "Dove",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What symbolizes Jesus Christ as the sacrificial offering for redemption?",
        answer: "Lamb",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which symbol is associated with discipleship and the early Christian community?",
        answer: "Fish",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Whenever you partake of these symbols, you proclaim the Lordâs death until he comes.",
        answer: "Bread and Cup",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: "Christmas Story",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "According to the Gospel of Matthew, what guided the Wise Men to find Jesus?",
        answer: "Star",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who is known for being the foster father of Jesus in the Christmas story?",
        answer: "Joseph",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the Christmas story, which angel appeared to Mary to announce the birth of Jesus?",
        answer: "Gabriel",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who were the first visitors to see the newborn Jesus in the stable?",
        answer: "Shepherds",
      },
      {
        question:
          "On the eighth day, when it was time to ____ the child, he was named Jesus",
        answer: "circumcise",
      },
    ],
  },
];

export const GetCategoryData = () => {
  return CategoryData.map((c, i) => ({
    ...c,
    questions: c.questions.map((qa, qi) => ({
      ...qa,
      used: false,
      id: `${c.name}-${qi}`,
      points: (qi + 1) * 100,
    })),
  }));
};
